good evening ladies and gentlemen a very
warm welcome to the icsa lombard general
insurance company limited's q3 and nine
month si 22 earnings conference call
from the senior management we have with
us today mr bhargav das gupta md and ceo
of the company mr gopal balochandran cfo
and cro
mr sanjiv mantri executive director
retail
and mr aloka garwal executive director
wholesale
please note that any statements comments
are made in today's call that may look
like forward-looking statements are
based on information presently available
to the management and do not constitute
an indication of any future performance
as future involved risk and
uncertainties which will cause results
to differ materially from the current
views being expressed
as a reminder all participant lines will
be in the lesson only mode
and there will be an opportunity for you
to ask questions after the presentation
concludes
should we need assistance during the
conference call please signal an
operator by pressing star then 0 on your
touchstone phone
i now hand the conference over to mr
bhalkartas gupta md and ceo ica
lombard general insurance limited
thank you and over to you
thank you
uh good evening to each one of you thank
you for joining the earnings conference
call of isis lombard general insurance
company for q3 and nine months of fi 22.
uh i hope you and your colleagues and
family members are all safe and healthy
i will give you a brief overview of the
industry trends and developments that
we've witnessed in the last few months
post this rca for mr gopal bala children
will share the financial performance of
the company for the quarter and nine
months ended december 31
the data for q3 fy 22
indicates that the momentum in the
economy activity has gained further
traction aided by expanding vaccination
coverage and release of pent-up demand
contact intensive indus services and
urban demand recruit on improving
consumer optimism
amidst this the researchers of covet 19
infections by way of the omicron variant
has created some sense of uncertainty
especially for service industry
while this may have some impact on the
near-term growth given the ramp up in
the vaccination program
its overall impact on the economy is
expected to be lower than the first and
the second wave
moving to the gi industry the industry
during qc fi 22 delivered mixed
performance
segments such as motor insurance
witnessed continued headwinds due to
heightened competitive intensity cheap
shortages in the four-wheeler segment
and weak festival demand in the
two-wheeler segment
health insurance on the other hand
continue to show robust growth primarily
driven by group health while growth in
retail health has moderated since q2 of
this fiscal due to base effect
as far as commercial lines are concerned
segments such as fire marine and
engineering lines witness strong growth
in sync with the current market
environment
overall the industry registered a growth
of eleven point two percent in nine
months of effect 22 and a growth of
eight percent in q3 of fi 22 as per
disclosures on the website of irdi
the combined ratio of the industry was
119.3 in h1 fi 22 as compared to 105.6
in h1 of 2021 based on available
information from public disclosures
excluding three companies
further the overall combined ratio of
private multi-line general insurance was
112.4 in h1 fi 2022 as compared to 103.2
in h121 excluding one company
moving to business impact this quarter
as you know we have been making
investments to benefit from the
opportunity that the current environment
has to offer especially in the retail
health segment these investments are
gradually steering growth for us thereby
enabling us to gain market share in our
preferred line of business
in that backdrop of the thousand uh
incremental head count to be added in
our retail health agency sales force we
have rolled out offers for 800 and have
successfully onboarded close to 400 of
them during this quarter
as a result we are seeing month-to-month
improvement in growth and we expect the
growth through this channel to
accelerate in the next few quarters as
the soil source starts getting
productive
as indicated during an earlier fall
there was a base effect on the health
benefit segment for the first three
quarters of f5.82 from the middle of the
current quarter the base effect started
to fade as a result of which health
business from our banker channels grew
by 15 in december of 2021.
going ahead we expect this channel to
continue to deliver robust growth
our one-stop solution for all insurance
and wellness needs i'll take care of has
surprised surpassed 1.1 million
downloads with successful submission of
over 95 000 claims and over 55 000
technically consultation requests
our objective is to get closer to our
customers by providing a unique digital
platform for continuous engagement to
help them take better care of their
health motor and other risks anytime
anywhere
as indicated in our previous earnings
calls in group health segment our
continuous
direct engagement with large corporates
enabled us to retain over 90 of our
customers at a higher price
thereby improving in in premium per life
since
june 2021 the underlying environment
suggests that the consumers are willing
to pay a higher premium for better
coverage and adopt technology for better
customer service thus creating an
opportunity for us to grow in this
segment
in motors we continue to come combat
challenges from the lack of motor tp
rate hike for over two consecutive years
heightened competitive intensity in the
motor od segment chip shortages in the
new private car sales etc
however our expectation is that these
are short-term challenges when we
take a closer look on ground on the
private car side the consumer sentiment
remains strong
and during the quarter we have continued
to focus on growing our market share in
certain key profitable sub segments
as far as the commercial lines are
concerned we have seen strong growth and
believe we are in that environment now
where the growth will continue
in current times the major major trend
has been the significant increase in
online buying by consumers
at ics lombard we have been continuously
investing in this front our digital one
team is set up like a full stack ensure
tech firm consisting experts across
functions operating together like a
fully functional entity within the
overall organizational framework
business source through our website
increased by 20 and q3 fi 22
within this our health business grew by
22.9
travel business grew by 156.9
and motor business grew by 11.9
business sourced by this
team through strategic alliance partners
in the digital ecosystem grew by 70
percent in q3 of f52
our digital one business is fully
empowered to deepmind customer data
fine-tuned customer outreach efforts
service customers to claim systems that
enable real-time communication and
thereby optimize cost of acquisition we
are excited on the progress of this
channel and believe it is all set to
drive benefit and benefit from the
longer term opportunity the current
environment is offering us
overall our focus on sustainable market
leadership continued through the third
quarter as we prioritize underwriting
discipline portfolio optimization and
growing in segments that are favorable
and fall within our risk appetite
we remain on track and are focused on
growth levels such as rendering our
distribution engine aided by lowered
base effect
realizing synergy rationalizing cost
while scaling up our preferred lines of
business servicing customers with
excellence
digital advance environment advancements
that will enable us to sustain the
return on equity objective over longer
term
i will now request gopal to take you
through the financial numbers for the
recently concluded quarter
thanks father and good evening to each
one of you
i will now give you a brief overview of
the financial performance of the company
for q3 and 915.22
we have put up the results presentation
on our website you can access it as we
walk you through the performance numbers
the effect of the day merge in the
financials has been incorporated in the
form of opening networks as on april 1
2021.
further the financials for the current
year represent members of the merged
entity
and the comparative number for the
previous year in the financials
pertaining to standalone icc lumbar and
hence they are not comparable
gross direct premium income of the
company was at
133.11 billion rupees in nine months at
five twenty two as against rupees one
zero five point two five billion in nine
months five twenty one the industry
reported a double digit growth of eleven
point two percent on a lower base for a
similar period
our gdp growth was primarily driven by
growth in preferred segments given that
our approach has always been growing
business sustainably
the fire segment gdpi was replaced 22
billion in nine months fi 22 as again
should be 17.48 billion in nine months
fi 21.
as indicated in our results presentation
the overall gdp of our property and
casualty segment was rupees thirty nine
point three four billion in nine months
fi twenty two as against thirty point
six one billion in nine months five
twenty one
on the retail side of the business gdp
of the motor segment was replaced fifty
eight point one five billion nine one
zero by twenty 22 as against rupees
51.48 billion and nine months at 521.
to harness the potential of these
segments we have been expanding our
distribution network to increase
penetration entirely for the entire four
cities
our agent including the point-of-sale
distribution increased to 81 969
as on december 31 2021 up from 78 000.35
as on september 30 2021.
the advanced premium was rupees 34.59
billion as at 31st december 2021 as
against
six point eight six billion
as at september thirty twenty twenty one
resultantly combined ratio was hundred
and eleven percent in nine months fi
twenty two as against ninety nine point
one percent in nine months fi twenty one
and hundred and fourteen point three
percent in h1 f5 2022
combined ratio 104.5 percent in quarter
three five twenty two as against ninety
seven point nine percent in quarter
three five twenty one and hundred and
five point three percent in quarter to f
by twenty two our investment assets rose
to rupee 374.54 billion at 31 december
up from rupees 371.95 billion at
september 30 2021. our investment
leveraged net of borrowings was 4.23
times at december 31 2021 compared to
4.27 times at september 30 2021.
investment income was at rupees 22.95
billion in nine months five twenty two
that's against rupees 16.59 billion in
nine months fi
a quarterly basis investment income was
at risk 6.9 billion in quarter 3 fbi 22
that's against rupees 5.68 billion in
quarter 3 fbi 21.
our capital gains was at rupees 6.01
billion in nine months at 522 as against
rupees 2.92 billion in nine months fi 21
capital gains in quarter 3 fi 22 was at
rs 1.31 billion as against rupees 1.08
billion in quarter three up by 21.
the expenses incurred of approximately
rupees 0.16 billion on account of the
demerger has been observed in the pnl
during nine months fi-22
as indicated in our previous earnings
call during the integration process we
were able to smoothly transition and
onboard our partners to seamlessly
operate with minimal disruption
our branch network as at december 31
2021 stood at 285
as against 431 as at september 30 2021.
apart from the immediate benefit this
transaction entails an opportunity to
unlock significant operational and
revenue synergies in times to come
we are on the right path on our roadmap
of realizing this energy benefits by the
second half of fiscal 2023.
our profit before tax was rupees 12.73
billion in nine months five twenty two
as against rupees fifteen point zero
four billion nine months at five twenty
one whereas profit before tax was four
point two one billion in quarter three
five twenty two as against four point
one eight billion in quarter three last
year
consequently profit of the tax
was rupees 9.59 billion in nine months
five twenty two as we get 11.27 billion
in quarter nine months at five twenty
one
whereas coffee doctor tax for this
quarter three stood at three point one
eight billion
as compared to rupees three 3.14 billion
and quarter three of 521. return on
average equity was fifteen point one
percent in nine months fi twenty two as
against twenty two point four percent in
nine months at five twenty one the
return on average equity for quarter
three five twenty two was fourteen point
six percent as against seventeen point
six percent in quarter three or five
twenty one solvency ratio was at two
point four five times at december thirty
one twenty twenty one as against two
point four nine times at september
thirty twenty twenty one it continued to
be higher than the minimum regulatory
requirement of 1.5 times
as i conclude i would like to reiterate
we continue to stay focused on
profitable growth
sustainable value creation and
safeguarding interest of policyholders
at all times
i would like to thank you all for
attending our earnings conference call
and we would be happy to take any
questions that you have thank you
thank you very much
we will now begin the question and
answer session
anyone who wishes to ask a question may
press star and 1 on the touchstone
telephone
if you wish to withdraw yourself from
the question queue you may press star
and 2.
participants are requested to use
answers while asking a question
ladies and gentlemen we will wait for a
moment while the question q assembles
[Applause]
the first question is from the line of
swarner mukherjee from bnk securities
please go ahead
yeah thank you for the opportunity sir
so i have couple of questions uh first
on the motorcycle if you could throw
some light on the
reason for the underwriting
uh
for this business
is this because of any kind of exchange
after amalgamation rpx
or any other driver of the
the underlying challenges more in terms
of the
distribution aggression that we are
seeing on the ground it's not not to do
with the merger on the merger front
actually we are quite happy with the way
things are progressing
um except for as we had earlier uh said
except for three or four oem dealership
we've in you know we've actually got
a complete synergy in terms of
benefiting from that distribution
channel um
we are also uh you know seeing growth
across most of the uh agency and the
other distribution channels that we've
uh
you know acquired through the
integration the real challenge on the
ground has been uh
you know we've always found that
whenever the growth slows down in the
market because of you know because of
various pressure right now we have
challenges the market because of chip
shortage for private car because of
online demand for two wheelers so
overall the industry is not growing as
fast as it is used to uh the motor
insurance industry and whenever the
substitutions happen we find that the
market as in our industry gets very
aggressive on sourcing
that's the real reason why uh the motor
book is underperforming if you look at
the largest from the cost side on the
loss ratio side it's also because of the
fact that the claims frequency has now
gone back to normal
first two quarters we had some benefits
because of relatively you know slower uh
you know utilization or lower
utilization because of some lockdowns
you know across the country that has
that went away in q3 so the lost issues
have climbed back up to uh what we
believe is more
normal so those are the real reasons
that we are seeing so it's more
underlying industry issues and you know
within that our uh experience rather
than any
in previous calls you had mentioned that
so what would be the trends now because
uh i think uh this kind of challenges
are continuing for quite some time
especially competitive intensity so are
you seeing situations improving and what
is what is the status in terms of you
know you had talked about price
increases also in second segment earlier
yeah what we had been saying that we
don't
expect that to happen or at least our
experience tells us that that should
happen from next year we don't expect
anything this year as we've been saying
uh there are two components on the price
increase one is the third party price
increase that is more uh terrific and
regulatory driven
again we believe that the industry needs
a direct price increase but that is as i
said you know driven by the regulator we
can't uh we don't control that uh but
two years we've not seen a price
increase we are hopeful that this year
we'll see one uh on the only side is
where we have greater control as an
industry and
as i said i think the industry benefited
a bit from the first quarter because of
uh lower usage and uh that's a benefit
that uh people probably have factored in
in terms of the admission so
we've never we've not we've been saying
that you don't expect a price correction
this year but we are hoping that we
should see that uh you know from next
year onwards historically we've never
seen you know two to three years of
uh price aggression uh in these two
years we've seen two coveted lockdowns
that has probably been the reason why
this is sustained for this longer period
uh from our perspective i believe we've
kind of
uh you know done most of the connections
that we wanted to
and on this base we are reasonably
confident that we'll start going from
the coming quarter onwards
okay that's that's very helpful sir uh
additionally on the
may i request to please reach on the
queue we have participants waiting for
sure
sure i'll join back thank you thank you
ladies and gentlemen in order to ensure
that the management is able to address
questions from all participants please
limit your questions to two per
participant if you have a follow-up
question you may rejoin the queue
the next question is from the line of
abhishek saraf from jefferies peace
corps
thanks for the opportunity um
and so i had question on with regard to
our retention so it appears that this
quarter we have had the higher retention
at around 76 percent versus what was
there in the previous two quarters of
this year around 66 60 or 68 percent
so what explains this stance which
category have we seen higher retention
and is it driven by the reinsurer or we
are doing it on our own volition that's
the first question uh second i noticed
that our investment yield both on the
policyholder investments or shareholder
investments have actually come down
uh
quarter and quarter
while the yield curve or the rates have
generally been on an upward trajectory
so if you can just help me understand
what has happened there also it will be
very helpful thanks a lot
so i'll ask opal to take the first one
into the mix of
with regard business the second one uh
in terms of the investment yield
the aggregate yield could be driven a
little bit by the
mix of capital gains that we have
overall the book is earning roughly
about seven percent
and when interest rates go up our mark
to market benefit that we are sitting on
the bond book that goes away but equally
the uh new flow that we get into the uh
you know investment portfolio that earns
a higher letter now given the overall uh
mix of the new flow versus the old stock
the new flow impact is very little
because it takes some time for you know
you know related to the overall size of
the book which is 38 000 crore the new
flow will be much much smaller so you
don't see that impact too soon
while you see the impact of the market
market benefit of the bond book going
going away but anyways one book for us
more or less has been kind of a more of
an atm strategy so we don't see a
problem with that
but as the mix of the book changes with
a greater flow coming in the increased
yield uh you know starts benefiting us
on the reinsurance i'll ask google to
answer the question yeah i wish i happy
new to you as well
i think on the retention side knows as
markov said there is no specific change
in the retention philosophy that pretty
much kind of remains the same
it's just that what you see in quarter
one typically you end up seeing a lot of
corporate renewals happening
where relatively the proportion of
reinsurance is higher and retention is
to that extent slightly lower
and whereas in quarter two i think if
you recollect what we have been saying a
consequent to the demerger we have also
kind of inherited the
crop book that barcelox had already kind
of committed to
and that book is something that got
booked in quarter two and which is why
you see a relatively lower retention for
quarter two
quarter three is typically the period
where you actually see a large part of
the business being under return on the
retail retail
franchise
predominantly motor and health where in
line with what we have mentioned no
change in the retention philosophy
typically these are small ticket
policies where our
retentions are relatively higher but
otherwise at an aggregate basis no
change in our retention philosophy as
such it is purely a function of what
kind of bricks of business that we have
underwritten in q1 and q2
sure thanks thanks vargas are quite
clear so basically one can then probably
going forward building that these kind
of thing the retention of the insurance
uh percentages would be broadly in line
with the mix of that particular quarter
uh just one thing if i can uh ask
on uh covet claims for the this quarter
if you can share the gopal that data how
was how were the net coverage claims for
us this quarter and uh i believe that in
last quarter he mentioned that we could
see some reservations so what has been
the
uh uh the trend there on covet claims in
this quarter if you can just throw some
like on there
what we had talked about was for the
first half of the year
now that number if you look at on a nine
month basis stands revised at about 5.29
so hence to that extent while
in line with what we are seeing as let's
say declining trend on the wave two
related uh covet cases
obviously in uh relative to the approach
of reserving that we are kind of built
in in quarter one
as i said nine month number stands at
about 5.29
having said that i think what it will be
important for us to kind of watch for
which is what we will do in quarter 4 is
this
wave 3 impact that has started to kind
of play out obviously early trends
in terms of the number of
cashless intimations that we are seeing
tends to be slightly uh maybe lower than
the peak what we had seen in wave two
but having said that obviously we will
monitor the development of intimations
because these are cashless requests
honestly we have to wait for in case if
there are any reimbursement claims that
gets intimated which typically happens
at the lag
but on the wave to related uh kovit
impact i think as i said nine month
number stands at about 5.29
well that's
thank you
the next question is from the line of
nadeshine from investec please go ahead
thanks for the opportunity sir i said uh
how should we think about combined ratio
and are we going forward
given that this was a pretty normal
quarter from uh
from a claims ratio perspective uh and
our combined ratio is around 105 for the
quarter uh so
how should we think about combined ratio
over next coming year uh also we expect
some
energy benefit to play out on the
operating cost uh so
uh should we expect this number to turn
towards under present over here over the
next couple of years
uh yeah
as we've been saying
we believe that i mean you know as you
know the merger just
the consolidation effectively happened
in the last month of last quarter so
we started taking uh most of the calls
that we need to take in terms of the
synergy benefit of the cost side
on the revenue side as i explained we've
uh we are quite happy with the way
things are playing out in terms of
the uh synergy with the existing
distribution that uh you know that that
bharti team had already built and we are
seeing growth coming through in some of
those partnerships as well
but the entire benefit for this as we've
been saying will take some time uh and
our sense is that we will start to see
the benefit play out maybe by you know
we have been saying fi 2024 but we think
it will probably be a bit uh earlier
than that so you know the second round
of next year we will start seeing that
benefit now if you look at the combined
uh you know on a pro forma basis uh baji
pre uh
deal announcement and i said number
three digital announcement if you need a
proforma integration
that would have been about 104 combined
uh so the question is how soon can we
bring that uh down now today what's the
situation is that the
core online business of icc robot is
also not at uh you know the 500 number
that we used to experience because of
all the pressures that we've talked
about uh so it may be
you know challenging to bring it under
100 that we have seen in the past but
directionally it will start uh coming
down and in terms of the synergies uh
maybe gopal can explain some of the
things work that has already happened
yeah i think
i mean we have been we have been kind of
talking about broadly three areas of
synergy right i think in line with just
to kind of uh
refresh uh i think tax energies is
something that i mean as we fight we
will be filing the returns of 2021 by
january 31st so we will
in line with what we have said earlier
we will be able to absorb
the full benefit of the carry power
losses
on the cost front i think as a part of
our operatic remarks which is what we
kind of put out i think we have looked
at the
overall
office infrastructure and clearly i
think we have been able to kind of uh
keeping in mind the policyholder
interest we have been able to kind of
look at what kind of existence do we
need to have in so far as physical
offices are concerned and clearly the
numbers as at the 31st december the
number of office networks stands revised
at about 285
so again so given the fact that this
rationalization of the office
infrastructure has happened in quarter
three and more towards the latter part
of the quarter so you will again start
to see some benefit of the synergies in
the form of cost
playing through from q4 onwards
equally i think we have been kind of
looking at various areas of uh
productivity improvements and
efficiencies which is what we are kind
of indicated on an earlier call to play
out over the next six to nine months so
there again we are on course
in order to be able to realize uh better
improvement in productivity when we look
at the other cost elements
the final cost element in terms of
technology related spend where again we
will be able to kind of see benefits on
synergy playing out that will take some
time because over the next 9 to 12
months is when we will be able to
significantly migrate
even let's say historical
data and other related information so
the impact of technology related spend
on this synergy front will start to play
through most probably towards
the second half of the next financial
year but otherwise on course to kind of
realize most of the cost elements that
we had thought about and the revenue
synergies as bhargav explained
is something that we will again start to
realize towards the second half of the
next financial period
sure
and secondly across
financial service segments we keep on
hearing noises around disruption
uh we have seen significant disruption
in some of the segments like broking and
now in our industry also uh a lot of new
age companies are coming up uh
in terms of distribution there is a new
manufacturing side on the gender
insurance uh some of these business
models have also succeeded outside india
so how do we think about uh from a
long-term perspective uh with respect to
these possibility of disruption to our
business
so uh you know i think we've been
discussing this uh pretty regularly you
know if you look at the uh
the scope for disruption there are you
know both in terms of ensure tech the
way people source policies they
people service policies very people
service claims
there is a tremendous scope for
disruption again using uh digital tools
that are
now available
similarly there is also some amount of
disruption that is possible in the
distribution side
now if you look at what we've been doing
is that on the on the first enter the
sourcing policies or
servicing uh you know policies through
uh
uh you know modern day technology that's
been an area that we've been investing
heavily uh our uh approach on the
business side has been as we you know
mentioned the opening says uh you know
statement
uh focus was to create a carve out a
team which focuses on the digital
disruption on the on the customer
acquisition side uh and we call it our
digital one team
where we've kind of created a team which
is uh
self-contained with uh you know all key
capabilities you know and with separate
uh you know location separate
philosophies in terms of
even people you know processes and that
team has been ramping up and uh we are
reason we are quite happy with the way
the team is growing business both in
terms of
uh tying up with uh digital uh ecosystem
partners and as i explained in this
quarter we've seen a 70 growth in that
uh business as also in terms of the
business that gets written on our
website and we've seen about 20 growth
in this quarter on on business written
on our website
now
the other thing that we have to study is
the
the uh you know honestly speaking the
fact that some of these players are
willing to uh lose a lot of money for
growth
uh we have to be a bit more calibrated
than some of them uh obviously our
philosophy has always been to
build a sustainable model
and we may not want to go to the level
of losses that some of them incur
but even without that we are reasonably
confident that we are able to go we will
be able to go this segment quite fast
towards that we are also uh you know
you know towards this end of this
quarter we've taken a fair amount of
calls
and we believe that that will reflect an
even faster growth in this channel going
at
on the claims side
we've been giving out some numbers
you know in terms of digital claim
settlement that you've seen both from
motor and health using ai ml etc those
numbers are increasing by the quarter
even this quarter we have a significant
increase in
the claims that we process through our
instaspect
service as also the
cashless authorization that we gave
using our ml features and similarly for
us in terms of the initiative on the
ielts take care side
that's the way we believe we will be
able to engage uh with customers even
better uh on a on a web-based platform
or a mobile app so rather and
build
greater connect while providing the
usual insurance services and there the
focus is not just in terms of the usual
things that you know insurance companies
provide but a lot more
uh you know services and features which
increase
you know engagement and potentially
reduces risk for our customers
so this is a this is a big trust area
for us
in terms of digital disruption
sorry to interrupt your request mr drain
to please rejoin the queue we have
participants reading therefore return
thank you
the next question is from the lion of
shriya shivani from clsa please go ahead
hi thank you thank you for the
opportunity hi sir i wanted to ask you a
question if i see the uh third quarter
uh
growth numbers for uh lombard and
including
the base so there has been a focus in
contraction for this quarter for the
combined entity while the industry or
the private players were at around five
to eight percent now motor we can see
has
grown much more 12 13 for the combined
entities while the private players have
still grown around six percent on the
health side again uh lombard uh
consolidated book is around three
percent growth for third quarter while
uh the industry and the private players
are significantly higher so so if you
can uh if you can give us some
understanding of how do you plan
what is your growth uh target it's not
target but how do you plan uh your
growth across these two segments because
these are your largest segments
basically and what uh what should we
expect for the
coming year or uh for the coming
quarters uh on on the growing side
let me take the two segments separately
uh let me start with motor
so
if you look at some of the commentary
that you've given on the motor side if
you look at the three sub segments
private car uh you know two wheeler and
uh commercial vehicles
we are a bigger player in terms of the
private car sub segment and even a
bigger player when you look at the share
of new our share of new is much higher
than our normal share of
uh business as a company and at a time
when uh the new sales have been muted
for reasons that all of us are aware
largely with chip shortage issues rather
than demand issue that has had a higher
impact on us than uh maybe the overall
industry
similarly if you look at our mix of
business two wheelers for us is a much
higher mix of business we have roughly
over 27 percent of our motor mix coming
from two wheelers industry mix would be
over roughly about 15
now two wheeler slow down has hence
affected us a bit more we you know from
a market share perspective we are fine
within the segment but from a mixed
perspective our uh you know growth gets
detected when two wheelers goes down on
the commercial vehicle side there has
been a growth again you know while for
the industry commercial vehicle is
roughly about 40 45
for us it's about 17 now so when that
segment grows faster than uh our sub is
then the other then relatively we
underperform having said that uh there
is also the pricing aggression point
that we've been making
and our sense is that most of the calls
that we wanted to take in terms of
correcting the portfolio has happened
and we remain uh
optimistic about growing or outgoing the
market from the coming quarters onwards
on the motor segment
on the health again this is an
unfortunate bit of a base effect one
because we were traditionally more of a
banker player and there was a basic base
effect in terms of uh
icc men stopping to distribute uh
you know our benefit products that had
some amount of impact on our overall
business
but separate from that now we are seeing
that growth come back so as i explain if
you look at even during the quarter uh
you know while overall number is your
rightly identified that the health
business has
you know undergone for the quarter but
if you look at just the month of
december we've outgrown the market on
the health detail health indemnity bills
as we are adding more uh
agents and distribution that we've
talked about and similarly with the bank
that base effect is largely paid out
played out and our overall bank
distribution in in the month of december
has grown uh by about 15
uh because the base effect has got
played out and we are uh optimistic that
this will start uh going from this
quarter onwards even the bank has
started restarted uh you know selling uh
non-benefit but our indemnity product as
an attachment just started so we'll have
to wait to see the impact it may say
take a bit of time
but overall uh i think the
base base effect headwinds are behind us
and uh and on top of it we are investing
in terms of the retail agency
distribution that we've talked about so
all in all we are quite optimistic about
growth from going going forward
and and uh also wanted to ask you uh
particularly on your health business uh
your group group business is a bigger
portion of your health portfolio so is
there any target you're putting on what
kind of mix you want to maintain between
retail and group in the health portfolio
we don't we take calls based on pure uh
you know risk selection i mean if let's
say
group health business is a
performance poorer we will cut down on
google's business what we are very happy
with is what we've been saying for some
time from june onwards after the wave 2
we went back to our corporate
clients for
price correction
you know obviously from from prospective
perspective not for the bank
and uh we said we will look at 50 to 20
price increase we are very happy to say
that for large corporates he's got an
even higher price increase on our
overall portfolio basis on a
quarter-life premium
we factored in the potential uh you know
some potential third wave also in the
price and we are quite happy that we've
retained more than 90 of our large
corporate accounts uh in spite of this
kind of a price increase so with this we
are reasonably confident about the group
book book right now uh we'll have to
watch for the
impact of covet wave 3 and the system
pricing so we don't put a target of mix
we put a target of profitability for
each of the segments
sorry to interrupt me i request my
shreya to please rejoin the queue ma'am
yeah sure thank you thank you
ladies and gentlemen in order to ensure
that the management is able to address
questions from all participants please
limit your question to one per
participant if you have a follow-up
question you may rejoin the queue
the next question is from the line of
rahul shah from b capital p squared
happy new year to you uh my question is
uh you said that there will around 400
kind of uh
agents added into the retail health side
but when i look at the numbers it is
some seventy from seventy eight thousand
it has gone to eighty two thousand
so this is uh how come only four hundred
in the rate retail
what the 400 number is our own sales
force that we hire on our rolls
the number that you are talking about is
the agent count so what we do is you
know these people join uh our company
and then they recruit agents who are not
on our own these are commission agents
side agents or point of sale agents so
these are two different numbers now when
we get these 400 people as we
mentioned you know in the in the second
uh earnings conference call we wanted to
recruit about thousand or you want to
add about thousand sales force in the in
the retail agency uh channel these are
people that will take on roles each of
them will then go out and hire
agents to do the distribution
but for our 400 of them have joined this
quarter then they will now go and you
know hire more agents and they those
agents will then produce business on the
ground
thank you
the next question is from the line of
prison from otila please go ahead
yeah hi happy new year everyone
a loss ratio uh in the quarter and uh
you know last previous quarter we had
some
uh 67 curves of
the
reserve release on the health book uh so
you know like to like comparison what
would have been the uh
ratio and looking at the motor tp price
side uh where are we in the sense
talking about it or
what are the processes that are needed
for the price i can has anything been
started from uh
let me take the first part uh first
pressure uh on the on the first one on
the health loss ratios i think when you
when you look at the
investor deck we have put out the
numbers which includes health and
accident uh put together just on the
health side if you were to look at what
are two loss ratios for the overall
health book was 77.7
quarter three that number stands at
about 82.7
and if you look at quarter three last
year
uh which is for isis lombard on a
standalone basis the overall health loss
ratio stands at about 88.1
those are three numbers uh q2 77.7
q3 of current year 82.7
and q3 of last year il on a standalone
basis at 88.1 so those are three numbers
that's in response to the first question
appears your second point on
the release of reserves that we had seen
in quarter two which is what i kind of
talked about
for the first half we had a net covered
impact of about 5.61 billion rupees
that's for the first half of the year
that number if you look at on a nine
month basis now stands revised at about
5.29 billion rupees
so hence to that extent i think uh
relative to the
trend line what we are seeing on account
of wave 2 covet cases i think the number
stands devised at about 5.29
as we as i mentioned i think obviously
what we will have to wait for is this
new wave 3 that has come through
what impact does it have both in terms
of count of intimation and two in terms
of average claim size i think as we move
forward in this quarter i think we will
be able to give share better insights
subsequently the initial trend seems to
suggest
when we look at the cashless count in
terms of intimations on wave 3
relative to the peak that we had seen in
wave 2 the number of integrations under
wave 3 seems to be far lower so that's
one trend line but early early trends we
will have to wait as i said uh for more
data to come through even on the claim
size as we speak maybe it looks like
things the cases that are getting
intimate are relatively milder and hence
to that extent may be a 10 to 15
lower average killing size than what we
would have normally seen in a
relative quarter that's what early
trends are obviously will have to wait
for for further intimations as and when
we
get those informations so that's one
your second point on motor third party i
think we have been talking about the
price increase unfortunately we have not
seen a price change happening over the
last couple of years
having said that i think we have also
been talking about let's say increase in
in fact the average claim payouts
consequent to various code judgments
that we have seen over the last couple
of years
the expectation that we have is maybe as
we head into lifted maybe fi 23
hopefully we should be able to see some
form of a draft guideline getting put
out in terms of increasing motor third
party pricing
thank you
the next question is from the line of
sanket goda from spark capital please go
ahead
yeah thank you thank you for the
opportunity uh
we have seen a significant increase in
the optics on quarter on quarter basis
if you see the sales promotional
advertisement spend has increased almost
welcome eight percent q and q
um this is just one i wanted to
understand uh uh why why it has gone up
uh uh given given it's a combined entity
um we we thought this number will will
come down uh compared to compared to
what you have done in second quarter and
and and also just wanted to understand
this costs in the park itself
so so
if if there are low hanging source like
branch racialization and the employee
rationalization
then then what is the likely absolute
cost you could be saving during fi 23
and fi 24 so that your optics ratios uh
from somebody
uh uh uh could could substantially
improve in 23 and 24 compared to what we
are seeing right now around 35 percent
is what we have
30 is what we are seeing is right now
for the for the combining gtx of
commission
so maybe some case to your first
question on the sales promotion trend i
think maybe you have to always look at
the overall
expense ratios number in the context of
the mix of business that we have
i think as i kind of mentioned in one of
the responses to the earlier question q3
typically happens to the period where we
see typically bulk of the retail
business heating source
for example the mix of motor within let
us say whatever volumes of business that
you would have that done in let's say q2
and q3 you will find
motor contribute contributing to a
relatively larger proportion of uh
gross return premiums and hence to that
extent correspondingly is where you will
get to see the cost of sourcing getting
reflected in so far as expense numbers
are concerned having said that i think
when you look at the aggregate
expense ratio numbers for quarter two
that number was at about 35.4 percent
this i am talking about both operating
expenses plus commissions put together
for quarter two that number was about
35.4
that number is actually kind of slightly
uh come off
and that number stands at about thirty
four point nine percent so hence to that
extent we have actually seen
uh maybe a point five percent
improvement in the overall
uh management expense ratios uh in
quarter three compared to quarter two uh
so that so that's that's the
uh trend line that one would obviously
want to kind of uh
see as we kind of head into the
subsequent quarters uh if your point on
let's say some of the cost energy is
getting paid out which is what we
explained your point is absolutely right
all the office infrastructure space is
what i again responded to one of the
earlier questions if you look at
december 31 our office number stands
devised at about 285 as compared to
almost more than 400 plus offices which
we had towards the end of september so
we have clearly been able to kind of get
benefits of rationalization on the
office space a large part of it happened
towards the second half of quarter three
and hence to that extent
the impact in the form of benefits on
cost is something that you will start to
see it playing through in the q4 number
onwards
the same thing is what we would
obviously also want to see improvement
in efficiencies and productivity playing
out
even when it comes to on the people's
front again the impact of which is
something that we will see over the next
i would say six to 12 months kind of
time period the trajectory that one
would take is what i think vargo also
responded in so far as the combined
ratio is concerned again when you look
at quarter two combined we were at about
105.3
and over the period i think you would
obviously want to try and see if you can
start seeing improvement in combined as
we head into this uh subsequent quarters
that's how the cost energies would play
out every cost element is being looked
at and some of the
immediate benefits is something that we
already started to see and certain
elements of cost particularly as i said
on the technology side will play through
towards the second half of fy23
thank you
ladies and gentlemen you are requested
to please limit your question to one per
participant if you have a follow-up
question you may rejoin the queue
the next question is from the line of
avena singh from mk global peace corps
[Music]
yeah hi good evening
uh
two questions one firstly on that you
know your retail health claims ratio
seems to be higher size if you three
despite some 30 odd crore of you know
reserve religious uh
adjustment so was it sort of uh in
certifying due to increasing frequency
of non-code or delayed procedures or was
there some sort of a change on the you
know uh severity sides so that's on the
detailed health part
and secondly on the motor side uh now we
have talked a lot about competition what
uh and margot told that okay or rarely
it has happened that two three years of
intense competition but one thing that's
different in this time of competition
is that there are a lot of new players
like uh they have been funded or being
funded on the patterns of you know the
futuristic uh
initial tech business where sort of uh
you know the justice period or
willingness to take losses is pretty
high for longer period and on the other
hand you have that the you know that the
large incumbents struggling to just
maintain their top line of course they
have been uh recapitalized so their
ability again to drag you know the
pricing is better uh i mean at least
higher this head so these are two
questions so how do you see that comp i
mean motor only companies and easy now
we asked great questions uh on the first
one uh it was largely because uh
elevated frequency of non-copic claims
that we see
we've been talking about it and in q3 we
had both medical acute cases which is
basically the dengue malaria cases which
kind of
you know kind of continued from q2
usually it's linked to the monsoon
seasons it's continued in the early part
of q3
and separately on top of that the
elective surgery numbers have been
quite high for q3
thirdly signs in q4 both those you know
medical acute cases came down in the
second half of q3 and even electric
surgeries right now is again trending
down but we'll have to watch this trend
for uh for a period in terms of acs very
similar to the number that we gave in
the last earnings call
over a two-year period we've seen
roughly about twenty percent increase so
about nine to ten percent uh annualized
increase in average game size is what we
are seeing uh which is largely a medical
inflation that we are seeing uh we will
have to again wait to see if this is
structural we explain the reason why we
think this is happening in terms of uh
additional tests upp suits etc uh but
you know till covet plays through this
will remain and then you know and
thereafter we'll have to wait to see if
this is structured so that's on the
health side
on the motor side you know your point is
absolutely valid uh in the past we've
not seen a
kind of a pe-funded entity which is just
going for growth
we've had disciplined
you know insurers who've come into the
market
so that risk is there having said that
we uh
we believe that um
from our perspective we've taken the
necessary calls that we wanted to uh
this year and we are reasonably
confident that on this base will
continue to grow on the motor book
i'm hoping that there will be some price
correction next year because of tp etc
but even otherwise we kind of geared up
to handle the sector
we've done a lot of granular analysis
during this year to prepare ourselves
for a situation where
you know this market continues to remain
aggressive
and we will still be able to compete
with ourselves
thank you
the next question is from the line of
sakash kapariya from moneygate portfolio
managers please go ahead
yeah but thanks for the opportunity
you know bhargava you mentioned about
you know the app downloads 1.1 million
so you know are we happy with this
number and can you share some customer
experiences because you know the app has
certain very good features like a
consultation or a diet planning
so you know how is the customer
experience been because you know some of
these things once you know
they are appreciated and kick in
automatically you know stickiness and
cross-sell can improve for us and you
know dental insurance there was some tie
up so is it you know under the same
policy are you know some of these uh
initiatives for creating a more
differentiation at our retail level kind
of
focus which is absolutely absolutely
correct you know this is exactly our
thought process on the on the benefit of
the app from a longer term perspective
if you look at the number 1.1 billion is
just scratching the surface
we launched this app
about two years back
largely focused on the
business to employ segment which is
basically the group health segment for
uh you know employees of our corporates
at that point in time our thought
process was this was a segment where
with whom we had hardly any engagement
uh individuals in in corporates wouldn't
even realize that the insurance was from
uh isis but unless they had a claim
and you know a small percentage of
people actually claimed so the whole
thought process was to build engagement
and then very rapidly we realized that
we needed to pivot and provide uh you
know a comprehensive uh you know
solution across product lines to these
uh
to these customers because the same
customer was an employee of a corporate
is also a retail uh you know insurance
customer of ours uh through maybe a
motor or some other policy
so we've been consistently pivoting and
you know or we've pivoted and we've been
consistently
building features on agile mode every 15
days we launched new new features on
that app and the number of downloads
that we are seeing is really a two-year
story right now we are adding almost
hundred thousand uh you know new uh app
users uh every month
on the service and the engagement we
we're watching it like a hawk uh there
is uh
you know we believe
you're absolutely right we believe this
will create stickiness and improve
process
we launched uh the renewal and the
crosstal uh you know upsell module uh in
the middle of this year uh around june
or july or august if i recollect and
month on month we are seeing good
traction in terms of uh people using the
app for
uh upselling or cross cross selling but
on a very small way so numbers are not
meaningful in the overall scheme of
things but the growth numbers are
quite phenomenal uh we'll wait for some
time before the numbers become
meaningful to talk about some of these
is my guess but overall we are very
clear that this is going to be a
tool to you know build a strong
engagement with our customers which will
in the long term help us with
across the lap cell you know and we
believe even loss ratio
thank you
ladies and gentlemen this was the last
question for today i would now like to
hand the conference over to mr bharara
does gupta for closing comments
thank you
you know again thank you everyone for
joining this call
you know we are available for
answering any other call separately feel
free to reach out in case you had a
question then time didn't permit us to
answer those then
and look forward to engaging you during
the quarter and thereafter thank you and
take care bye thank you so much thank
you
thank you
on behalf of ica lombard general
insurance that concludes this conference
thank you for joining us and you may now
disconnect your lines